LUCAS J. ECKMAN

(202)-642-6766 <u>lucas.eckman@gmail.com</u> <u>lucaseckman.com</u> <u>github.com/eckmLJE</u> <u>LinkedIn</u>

Full stack web developer with a lifelong passion for learning and problem solving, building on fresh experience in modern web development to take on new opportunities in software engineering. My approach to development and design is informed by my past experience managing complex projects in real estate development, creative placemaking, and live events. This broad professional background has equipped me with universal tools for working with teams through challenging processes.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript ES6, React.JS (Redux, ConnectedRouter, Thunk), Ruby on Rails, HTML5 + CSS3, SQL, Git
- RSpec, Mocha, Jest; Sass, Bootstrap, Semantic, Ant.design; SVG
- Python, C#, Unity VR with Google Cardboard

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

ConcertPlan - <u>lucaseckman.com/concertplan</u> - Github: <u>Front End</u> | <u>Back End</u>

Friend groups view upcoming concerts and tickets and make plans to go to concerts together

- Calls Ticketmaster API for up to the minute concert and ticket data.
- Implements user authentication with JWT and bcrypt.
- React.JS Front End, Rails Back End. Pure CSS with no UI framework. Redux, ConnectedRouter, Moment, and Thunk.

RoomSeek - <u>lucaseckman.com/roomseek</u> - Github: <u>Front End</u>

Apartment seekers find an available bedroom in an apartment by setting price and date filters

- > SVG elements render interactive, dynamic floor plans
- > Floor plans are generated programmatically from database attributes of rooms and furniture (length, width, shape, etc.)

Parsel - Blog Post - Github: Front End | Back End

Highlight, parse and comment text documents by highlighting text on the page linked to annotations

- Built in three phases: first in vanilla JS, then introducing React, and lastly Redux with Thunk and Connected Router.
- ReactJS Front End, Rails Back End, Semantic UI React CSS Framework

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

February 2014 - Present | Washington, DC

Bicycle Courier UrbanStems

> Deliver happiness by bicycle in the form of flowers, plants and gifts throughout DC.

Real Estate Development Consultant

March 2015 - March 2018 | Washington, DC

Clients: Ditto Residential, Brook Rose Development, D.B. Lee Development & Construction

- Achieved 100% occupancy in initial lease-up of two rental properties in Northeast DC, including cutting-edge co-living product, OSLO. Worked directly with CEO and Marketing VP to troubleshoot leasing strategy and processes.
- > Drove sprawling Union Market warehouse redevelopment project from pre-acquisition to unanimous DC Zoning Commission approval. Developed project prospectus and presented to international hotel brands and operators. Collaborated with DC non-profit organization CulturalDC to design subsidized arts program to serve as signature cultural attraction within hotel.

Operations Director

September 2013 - March 2015 | Washington, DC

Collective Group

>> Bootstrapped operations processes for 300-member social impact film conference held during Sundance Film Festival with minimal staff. Event featured documentary film panel discussions, gourmet dinners, live musical performances, and market activations for major sponsors on Main Street in Park City.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School - Completed August 2018. Full Stack Web Development Immersive Program: Ruby on Rails, JavaScript and React.

Columbia University - New York, NY - 2007 to 2009 **Kenyon College** - Gambier, OH - 2004 to 2005